When you come into an existing code base and you
want to make changes to it,
one of the things you want to make sure is that
you don't break anything that's already running.
I'm going to show an example of how you do this
using Claud code on this open source Outer Space
app.
It's a microservice that
when it gets called
it'll go and fetch data from the correct backend
system.
You can see in my main here
that I've added a new
launches
summary endpoint.
It should go and actually summarize data from the
most recent launches
from the SpaceX API.
As part of this you can see a couple different
things got touched.
you know some of these,
the interfaces,
the handlers in MySpaceX,
not everything has necessarily had tests added to
this.
So I'm gonna use
Claude code here and,
and have it go and get real data,
real
traffic for outer space
from the production
environment
and test these changes.
What this is going to do is
it'll actually prompt CLAUDE to go figure out how
it can go and get real traffic.
can see here
it found this tool called ProxyMock which is
available on my machine and it wants to go
and
pull
data.
the directory doesn't exist.
It'll figure all this stuff out.
go make the directory.
So it's making a proxymock directory now it's
going to go
fetch
existing traffic.
This is one of the problems
that
the claude code context may not understand how the
app really runs.
So by using this mcp it can go and
find out data about how the app really works,
pull this information
down.
it discovered
service had a slightly different name and it can
go and grab the traffic here.
And when this is working we should get this
proxymonk directory,
get populated
with new data
from how the application is really running
then it will take a look,
compare the changes in this traffic
compare that to the new code changes that have
just been added here.
Okay
so it took a couple minutes but it did go and pull
down the traffic and we can see it's got a fresh
recording.
Today is November 25th so it got data from today
and
each of these endpoints actually has
a couple of different
examples
of sample traffic.
And we can see here for
here is the get request to the rockets endpoint
and exactly how
SpaceX responded.
this is great.
understands
the New code as well as the existing code.
And now what it's going to do is actually run a
mock server,
simulate the production environment.
then it will run the code against the simulation
and see if it finds any issues.
So again
I've got it where it's prompting me each time for
each of these commands so that we can see
what they are running.
But you'll notice here it created a new directory
which says it's mocking the endpoint
down here in the output we can see the outer space
binary itself
and boom,
boom,
boom.
It's going
run through each of the
API calls and make sure
the responses are coming back as expected.
I just noticed this NASA Endpoint is having an
error
that actually says it's matching
the production behavior.
we've been able to see here that there is an issue
with the production traffic and I was able to
replicate that on my machine.
that kind of thing is actually helpful.
And we'll see at the end if
LLM asks
checking that NASA endpoint if we want to do
something
something about it or why we're getting that kind
of error.
So
the mock server is working well.
This endpoint doesn't exist in the production
traffic.
So
what's
it going to do here?
That makes sense because we've added a new
endpoint and
original endpoint may have not been in the
recording.
it should get us
a new recording here.
that shows us the
new data that's being added.
Let me check here.
that's a cache miss,
but the mock server passed it to the real API and
it returned.
Okay,
so even
that exact call was
the recording
actually went and passed through to the live
system.
So far all I'm doing is hitting enter for it to
keep running through the commands.
I haven't written any other prompts other than the
the first original one which was to download
production traffic.
Give this a second
it to figure out what it did.
So the new feature works.
The mock behavior didn't
match,
but it passed it through.
NASA Endpoint is having a problem and even has
told me what the problem is from the NASA
endpoint.
here we go.
This is the feedback I'm looking for.
All the tests are passing.
The new feature is working correctly,
although it did note that we're having one
with our current
environment.
This is a way that you can take
the context that you have of having the source
code and adding
more data about how this API really runs in
production so that the combination can be used
together to make
more powerful for
writing new code with your AI coding agent.
Feel free to check this out on ProxyMock IO.
Thank you.