One of the really cool things about using
development tools like Cursor is
it can dramatically speed up your application
development.
In this case,
I'm  using Cursor on an existing application to
add a new API call that wasn't in there before.
It's great.
It went and did the work.
It figured out how,
it needs to
go make the specific code changes.
but
my challenge here is validating that this code
actually works.
I'm going to flip over to the editor view here so
I can show you.
This is my microservice here.
What  I was just asking it to do was run all the
unit tests,
make sure that you didn't break any kind of
functionality here.
But we all know unit tests are not enough.
We're not actually running the code itself.
So I want to run integration tests.
I've got a tool called ProxyMock and I actually
have instrumented this application outer Space
in my cluster and I can use Proximock to download
a snapshot of how this is currently working.
So,
download a live
snapshot of  Outer Space,
go
using ProxyMog and run integration tests.
So
what I want to make sure here is because
I've made changes to a bunch of the different
library functions and they're used all throughout
the project,
I want to make sure that I didn't break anything.
So proxymock is a local
cli.
It's running on my machine and it exposes an MCP
interface.
That means the
LLM can call it.
I'm not going to the Internet.
It's a local
call on my own machine.
And  you have to authenticate,
when you run proxymonk.
So  you can see here it's actually running this
pull remote recording
and  it's gone and created a ProxyMock directory
and actually pulled data out on exactly how this
application is running right now.
So,
so this is a live timestamp.
I'm recording this
on
November 19th.
So this is fresh data from how the application is
running right now.
And it's going to go and use that data
so that it can mock a complete local environment,
simulate these downstream dependencies that I may
not have available
on my local machine
and
execute the code.
When it's all done,
it's going to tell me if my  new code changes
happen to break anything at all.
The advantage here,
above and beyond unit tests,
is I can understand
how this will actually functionally
run because,
it will
execute the code.
It'll
Run it on my machine.
Even if I have dependencies
on other systems
those will get automatically mocked out.
You can see there's a mocked directory here.
That's how
ProxyMock can mock out and simulate things like
third party APIs,
cloud services,
even databases can get mocked out.
And  I don't have to write any code to do this
and I don't have to install a bunch of libraries
or have
Cursor
write a bunch of  throwaway code.
It's doing it based on
real
observations of the traffic.
it's in markdown format so it knows exactly how
calls
are made to my API,
exactly how my API responded and it even includes
things like the third party calls.
So here's a call to the SpaceX endpoint and how
SpaceX really responded.
Live,
HTTP headers,
body,
all of that is
available
to
ProxyMock
so that  the
Cursor can use this additional context to create
an actual local simulation.
Make sure that we didn't
break anything.
It actually looks like it's adding
some additional data in here to test our new API
as well,
which is good.
And then in the end it actually will generate new
observations
and can
compare
the observations
of   how the code changed,
if the code changed at all and compare it to the
live.
So
it says here,
it downloaded a fresh
snapshot,
it ran the mock server,
it
replayed 20 calls that were from the live
environment,
made sure that nothing broke
and
all the other endpoints were validated.
Integration test completed successfully.
This is the confidence you need to know.
Okay,
I've got good changes here.
Let me keep all these changes and check it in and
push it in.
Feel free to check out more information about this
on speedscale.com
and search for Proximalk.